<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[3D Printing Letter]]></title>
  <link href="http://3dprintingletter.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://3dprintingletter.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-08T12:33:16+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://3dprintingletter.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[3D Printing Letter]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An interview with Tracy Turner - Project Manager at Makerbot]]></title>
    <link href="http://3dprintingletter.github.com/2013/03/08/an-interview-with-tracy-turner-project-manager-at-makerbot/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-08T11:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://3dprintingletter.github.com/2013/03/08/an-interview-with-tracy-turner-project-manager-at-makerbot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, I&#8217;ve had the privilege to talk to Tracy Turner, who is a Project Manager at Makerbot. I asked her a few questions about life at the Makerbot offices in NY. For those who don&#8217;t know <a href="http://www.makerbot.com/">Makerbot</a>, they make <a href="http://store.makerbot.com/replicator.html">really</a> <a href="http://store.makerbot.com/replicator2.html">cool</a> <a href="https://store.makerbot.com/replicator2x.html">stuff</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->




<br/>


<ul>
<li>Hi Tracy. Tell us about yourself. How did you end up at MakerBot?</li>
</ul>


<p>The best answer I can give as to how I ended up at MakerBot® is that, “somewhere in my
youth or childhood, I must have done something good.”</p>

<p>The trajectory that brought me to MakerBot is certainly not linear! Originally, I was a
classically-trained French horn player who, along the way, found a niche in “downtown” and
experimental music. Looking for a new challenge, I acted on my interest in how knowledge is
created and shared, and returned to school in Library and Information Science. I identified
that I had to find a niche for myself with cutting-edge technology and science because I thrive
on being around the creative energy and excitement as people are disrupting old systems
and forging completely new pathways.</p>

<br/>


<ul>
<li>Tell us about working at MakerBot. What&#8217;s the vibe like? What&#8217;s it like in the office?</li>
</ul>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='We have more than 15,000 MakerBot Desktop 3D printers in use by
engineers, industrial designers, architects, entrepreneurs, educators, and people who just like
to make things, and that figure is growing every day.'>
The vibe at MakerBot is incredible. Our office reminds me of a beehive – it is abuzz with
creative flow and people working ridiculously hard. The only difference is that bees don’t have
so much fun!</p>

<p>We have this absolutely stunning new office in MetroTech Center in Brooklyn, so the physical
environment is inspiring and aesthetically pleasing. We’re up high and against a backdrop of
a 360 degree view of downtown Brooklyn and New York City. Inside our walls there is an
amazing assortment of incredibly friendly and hardworking “bees” who are all absolutely
brilliant and scary smart.</p>

<p>The MakerBot employee lounge/café is a good place for us to hang out and talk and dream and scheme. There is usually something goofy going on somewhere in the office – a quadocopter flying around, someone in sales dressed in a suit and tie because he lost a bet the day before to someone in customer support – but the overall impression you get from the  office is that everyone is absolutely focused and demanding a lot of themselves. Working at MakerBot, you take pride in playing a role in something bigger than yourself, of being part of a revolution that will change the way the world creates and makes. You can sense this in the office and in the way people treat each other.</p>

<p>MakerBot is also growing at a fast pace. Two years ago, we had 16 percent of the market
share of all 3D printers (industrial and personal); in 2011, MakerBot had 21.6 percent market
share; and in 2012, MakerBot estimates that share grew to 25 percent of the overall 3D
printer market. We have more than 15,000 MakerBot Desktop 3D printers in use by
engineers, industrial designers, architects, entrepreneurs, educators, and people who just like
to make things, and that figure is growing every day.
</span></p>

<br/>


<ul>
<li>What are your responsibilities as a Project Manager at MakerBot? What does a
typical day at MakerBot look like for you?</li>
</ul>


<p><span class='pullquote-left' data-pullquote='My job is to make sure that everyone knows how to get their hands on the information they need to do their jobs and collaborate seamlessly, and can do so easily.'>
One thing I value most is that there is no typical day at MakerBot! Projects are coming to us
so fast and furiously, and there is such variety in the projects that we undertake, that each
day has unique challenges. The common factor for me is the facilitating of communication
and the efficient sharing of knowledge.</p>

<p>MakerBot has grown very quickly. It wasn’t that long ago that you could simply lean across desk or holler to the other side of the room to get answers to questions. There are growing pains that are inevitable when organizations grow, and optimizing the systems for sharing knowledge is essential for smoothing the way for all. That is where I come in. My job is to make sure that everyone knows how to get their hands on the information they need to do their jobs and collaborate seamlessly, and can do so easily. I also help to track projects and make sure everyone has what they need to work together and sharing information easily.
</span></p>

<br/>


<ul>
<li>Are you actively involved in 3D printing? Do you own a 3D printer? If so, what kind of
things do you like creating or printing?</li>
</ul>


<p>I’m in the beginning stages of being actively involved. I’ve completed my first print (a print of
my son’s head from the MakerBot 3D Photo Booth at the MakerBot Store) and have attended
classes on using a MakerBot Replicator 2 Desktop 3D Printer at the MakerBot Store in New
York City. As much as I really, really want a MakerBot, I don’t need to have one because I
can use the ones at the office whenever I want (if I just had the time!) There are thousands of
ideas of things I want to print or design myself, but I next want to print some desk accessories
for new desk at MetroTech and also a Millennium Falcon for my son.</p>

<br/>


<ul>
<li>Is there anything special about the MakerBot offices you&#8217;d like to mention? Any
perks for people interested in joining MakerBot?</li>
</ul>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='And importantly, the thrill of leading the next
industrial revolution – and having 3D printers all over the office that can make anything you
want or need.'>
There are tons of perks to working at MakerBot – the first of which is that you get to work with
the smartest and nicest people in the world. And importantly, the thrill of leading the next
industrial revolution – and having 3D printers all over the office that can make anything you
want or need. MakerBot is the collision of technology with the future so, in order to get to the
future quickly, we have a Tardis (a time machine from Dr. Who) in our lobby. We’ve got great
views from our windows to inspire us, and I always know how much the Powerball jackpot is
from the billboard by the Brooklyn Bridge, as seen from the windows by our coffee/hot
chocolate maker we have in the kitchen. Daily fresh fruit helps fuel the body as well as the
mind, and there are quite a few foodies working at MakerBot, as someone always seems to
be bringing in something interesting to share.</p>

<p>And the Munchkins&#8230; There seems to be an endless stream of Munchkin donuts. As part of
each new hire’s first day at MakerBot, they hand out Munchkins to all as they are introduced
around the office. And Yoga Tuesdays to work off those Munchkins&#8230;</p>

<p>We are a close-knit community and have different clubs for various activities we enjoy doing
together – games, knitting, eating, etc.
</span></p>

<br/>


<ul>
<li>Is MakerBot hiring? :)</li>
</ul>


<p>Yes! MakerBot continues to grow in so many areas. Go to our <a href="http://www.makerbot.com/">website</a> and click on “MakerBot Careers” at the bottom of the page to see  current listings. If the job you want isn’t listed, send in your resume anyway using the <strong>“I DON’T SEE THE RIGHT FIT but I want to apply for open-yet-unposted positions!”</strong> option.</p>

<br/>


<p>So&#8230; life at Makerbot seems very interesting. Thanks a lot Tracy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new blog for 3D Printing]]></title>
    <link href="http://3dprintingletter.github.com/2013/03/08/a-new-blog-for-3d-printing/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-08T10:54:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://3dprintingletter.github.com/2013/03/08/a-new-blog-for-3d-printing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi!</p>

<p>I finally did what I planned to do a long time ago, create a 3D Printing blog to support my weekly <a href="http://www.3dprintingletter.com/">3D Printing newsletter</a>. This blog is a permanent work in progress. The main purpose is not necessarily to provide 3D Printing news (that&#8217;s already done by many other blogs, websites and my own 3D printing newsletter). So you might ask what this blog will be about then. Well, the short answer is we&#8217;ll see. The slightly longer answer is:</p>

<ul>
<li>Interviews with 3D printing pioneers</li>
<li>Hands-on 3D Printers</li>
<li>Original articles about 3D Printing that have not been reported by news outlets</li>
</ul>


<p>You&#8217;ll hear from me. Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
